<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>org.ksnip.ksnip</id>
    <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
    <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
    <developer_name>Damir Porobic</developer_name>
    <name>ksnip</name>
    <summary>Cross-Platform Screenshot tool with annotation features</summary>
    <description>
        <p>
​        Ksnip is a Qt based cross-platform screenshot tool that provides many annotation features for your screenshots.
​        </p>
        <p>Features:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Supports Linux (X11, Plasma Wayland, GNOME Wayland and xdg-desktop-portal Wayland), Windows and macOS.</li>
            <li>Taking screenshot of a custom rectangular area that can be drawn with mouse cursor.</li>
            <li>Taking screenshot of last selected rectangular area without selecting again.</li>
            <li>Taking screenshot of the screen/monitor where the mouse cursor is currently located.</li>
            <li>Taking screenshot of full screen, including all screens/monitors.</li>
            <li>Taking screenshot of window that currently has focus.</li>
            <li>Taking screenshot of window under mouse cursor.</li>
            <li>Take screenshot with or without mouse cursor.</li>
            <li>Capture mouse cursor as annotation item that can be moved and deleted.</li>
            <li>Customizable capture delay for all capture options.</li>
            <li>Upload screenshots directly to imgur.com in anonymous or user mode.</li>
            <li>Upload screenshots via custom user defined scripts.</li>
            <li>Command line support, for taking screenshot and saving it to default location, filename and format.</li>
            <li>Filename wildcards for Year ($Y), Month ($M), Day ($D), Time ($T) and Counter (multiple # characters for number with zero leading padding).</li>
            <li>Print screenshot or save is to pdf/ps.</li>
            <li>Annotate screenshots with pen, marker, rectangles, ellipses, texts and other tools.</li>
            <li>Annotate screenshots with stickers and add custom stickers.</li>
            <li>Add watermarks to captured images.</li>
            <li>Global HotKeys for taking Screenshots (Currently only for Windows and X11).</li>
            <li>Tabs for Screenshots and images.</li>
            <li>Open existing images via dialog, drag-and-drop or paste from clipboard.</li>
            <li>Run as single instance application (secondary instances send cli parameter to primary instance).</li>
            <li>Pin Screenshots in Frameless windows that stay on top of other windows.</li>
            <li>Many configuration options.</li>
        </ul>
    </description>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">org.ksnip.ksnip.desktop</launchable>
    <url type="homepage">http://ksnip.org</url>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Main Window</caption>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/4nMcbnF.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <caption>Crop Window</caption>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/1aQZID6.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <caption>Snipping Window 1</caption>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/gXolSAI.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <caption>Snipping Window 2</caption>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/ATGeYvI.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <caption>Snipping Window 3</caption>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/dMrqJpq.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <caption>Settings Dialog</caption>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/5YaVTV4.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <caption>Sticker Settings</caption>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/PCLxIUo.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <caption>Imgur History Links</caption>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/AQuHhDR.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <provides>
        <id>ksnip</id>
        <id>org.ksnip.ksnip.desktop</id>
    </provides>
    <update_contact>damir.porobic@gmx.com</update_contact>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
    <releases>
        <release type="stable" version="1.9.0" date="2021-03-01T00:00:00Z">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>New: Add option to select the default action for tray icon left click.</li>
                    <li>New: Open/Paste from clipboard via tray icon.</li>
                    <li>New: Show/hide toolbar and annotation settings with TAB.</li>
                    <li>New: Add setting for auto hiding toolbar and annotator settings.</li>
                    <li>New: Allow setting transparency of not selected snipping area region.</li>
                    <li>New: Resize selected rect area with arrow keys.</li>
                    <li>New: Copy a screenshot to clipboard as data URI.</li>
                    <li>New: Provide option to open recent files.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add function for loading translations.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add a new tool for creating resizable movable duplicates of regions.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add support for hiding annotation settings panel.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add config option for numbering tool to only set next number.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Allow manually changing canvas size.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Canvas background color configurable.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Zoom in and out with keyboard shortcuts.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Zoom in and out via buttons from UI.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Deleting item outside image doesn't decrease canvas size.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release type="stable" version="1.8.1" date="2020-12-30T00:00:00Z">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Changed: Allow changing adorner color for rect area selection.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Notarize ksnip for macOS.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Default font for numbering tool change to Arial.</li>
                    <li>Changed kImageAnnotator: Horizontally align text inside spin box.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: If file selection is cancelled during ksnip's file open dialog via tray icon, ksnip closes.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Cancel on Quit not work when editor is hidden.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Canceling rect area selection activates main window.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Enter key doesn't finishes resizing.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Missing version number in mac binaries.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Canceling save dialog show the option save path in the header.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Save-as Window does not get focus when using snap.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Editor can not be shown again after click close icon.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Icons and text boxes not correctly scaled under gnome with hdpi.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Window captures include non-transparent border of background on Gnome.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Annotating hidpi image downscales the result after being saved.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Brazilian Portuguese translation not loaded.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: error: control reaches end of non-void function.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Cursor in Text tool have too bad visibility.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: bumped SONAME without name change.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Entering multiple characters at once moves the text cursor only for one character.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Activating context menu while drawing item leaves item in error state.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Icons not scaled on gnome with hdpi enabled.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Text/Number Pointer and Text/Number Arrow don't inherit Text/Number Font in Settings.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release type="stable" version="1.8.0" date="2020-12-13T00:00:00Z">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>New: Pin screenshots in frameless windows that stay in foreground.</li>
                    <li>New: Support for unit tests.</li>
                    <li>New: Add brew cask package for ksnip.</li>
                    <li>New: Allow setting image quality when saving images.</li>
                    <li>New: Add support for cross-platform wayland screenshots using xdg-desktop-portal.</li>
                    <li>New: Add save and save as tab contextMenu items.</li>
                    <li>New: Add open directory context menu item on capture tabs.</li>
                    <li>New: Add copy path to clipboard context menu item on capture tabs.</li>
                    <li>New: Add option to delete saved images.</li>
                    <li>New: Add support for loading image from stdin.</li>
                    <li>New: Add screenshot options as application actions to desktop file.</li>
                    <li>New: Allow renaming existing images.</li>
                    <li>New: Make hiding main window during screenshot optional.</li>
                    <li>New: Open several files at once in tabs.</li>
                    <li>New: Allow modifying selected rectangle before making screenshot.</li>
                    <li>New: Option to keep main window hidden after a taking screenshot.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add Pixelate image area tool.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Zoom in and out.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add interface for adding custom tab context menu actions.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add drop shadow to captured images.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add grayscale image effect.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add numeric pointer with arrow annotation item.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add text pointer annotation item.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add text pointer with arrow annotation item.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Add option to automatically switching to select tool after drawing item.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Edit Text box with double click.</li>
                    <li>New kImageAnnotator: Resize elements while keeping aspect ratio.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Show all Screenshot options in System Tray.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Upload multiple stickers at once.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Follow pattern for monochromatic systray icon.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Pin window shows default cursor when mouse over it.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Cancel snipping area if no selection made after 60 sec.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Allow removing imgur account.</li>
                    <li>Changed kImageAnnotator: Draw point when clicking and releasing without moving cursor.</li>
                    <li>Changed kImageAnnotator: Zoom out less than 100%.</li>
                    <li>Changed kImageAnnotator: Change to select tool after adding new annotation item.</li>
                    <li>Changed kImageAnnotator: Move current zoom text to left side config panel.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Snap crashing when trying to take screenshot under Wayland.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: zh_Hans translation won't load.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Ksnip only saves the upper right part of the screenshot with HiDPI.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Main window not resized with new captures.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Brazilian Portuguese translation not loaded.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Blur radius not updated when changing current items settings.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Text tool opens many unix sockets.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Text No Border and No Fill shows shadow beneath text.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Item properties remain displayed after item is removed or deselected.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kImageAnnotator: Changing text box through editing text doesn't update resize handles.</li>
                    <li>Fixed kColorPicker: Border around colors is not centered.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release type="stable" version="1.7.3" date="2020-07-30T00:00:00Z">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Provide ksnip flatpak.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Install svg icon file in hicolor theme dir instead of usr/share/pixmaps/.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release type="stable" version="1.7.2" date="2020-07-29T00:00:00Z">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Changed: Stop upload script when process writes to stderr.</li>
                    <li>Changed: Upload script uses regex to select output for clipboard.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Ksnip becomes unresponsive when file dropped into it.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Ksnip window always visible on screenshots on Gnome Wayland.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Selecting path in Snap via file-chooser sets home directory to /run/user/1000.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: Snap not able to run custom upload script.</li>
                    <li>Fixed: kImageAnnotator: Tests fail to build with shared library.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>
</component>
